[
    {
        "question": "What organization manages the Olympic Games?",
        "options": [
            "International Olympic Committee",
            "UN Olympic Committee",
            "Olympic Club International",
            "World Olympic Organization"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "International Olympic Committee"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many rings are there on the Olympic flag?",
        "options": [
            "5",
            "6",
            "7",
            "9"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did Australia first participate in the Winter Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "1936",
            "1968",
            "1896",
            "1928"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1936"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country''s track-and-field team was banned from the 2016 Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Zimbabwe",
            "Russia",
            "Germany"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the standard distance of the modern Olympic marathon?",
        "options": [
            "13 miles 100 yards",
            "20 miles",
            "25 miles",
            "26 miles 385 yards"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "26 miles 385 yards"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which Olympic Games did the Olympic flame first appear?",
        "options": [
            "Amsterdam 1928 Olympic Games",
            "Antwerp 1920 Olympic Games",
            "Athens 1896 Olympic Games",
            "St. Louis 1904 Olympic Games"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Amsterdam 1928 Olympic Games"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which sport did Abhinav Bindra win the first individual gold medal for India?",
        "options": [
            "50-meter air rifle",
            "300-meter free rifle",
            "600-meter rifle",
            "10-meter air rifle"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "10-meter air rifle"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Olympic Village of which Olympic Games was later used to house juvenile offenders?",
        "options": [
            "Oslo 1952 Olympic Winter Games",
            "Cortina d''Ampezzo 1956 Olympic Winter Games",
            "Sapporo 1972 Olympic Winter Games",
            "Lake Placid 1980 Olympic Winter Games"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Lake Placid 1980 Olympic Winter Games"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has won the most Olympic gold medals in men''s field hockey?",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Canada",
            "Australia",
            "Germany"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did the modern Olympics start?",
        "options": [
            "122 BCE",
            "1642 CE",
            "1968 CE",
            "1896 CE"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1896 CE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Olympic athlete was awarded the Pierre de Coubertin medal in 2004?",
        "options": [
            "Abbey D''Agostino",
            "Nikki Hamblin",
            "Vanderlei Lima",
            "Emil Z\u00e1topek"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Vanderlei Lima"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Chinese Winter Olympic gold medalist?",
        "options": [
            "Liu Xiang",
            "Sun Dandan",
            "\n\nWang Chunlu",
            "\n\nYang Yang"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "\n\nYang Yang"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the Olympic motto \"Citius, altius, fortius\" mean?",
        "options": [
            "Faster, higher, stronger",
            "For the love of the game",
            "Achievement, fame, fortune",
            "In pursuit of greatness"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Faster, higher, stronger"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times has London hosted the Olympic Games?",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "2",
            "1",
            "4"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the headquarters of the International Olympic Committee located?",
        "options": [
            "Z\u00fcrich",
            "Lausanne",
            "London",
            "Dubai"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Lausanne"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did China host the Olympic Games for the first time?",
        "options": [
            "1992",
            "1984",
            "2002",
            "2008"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "2008"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was drug testing introduced in the Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "1984",
            "1968",
            "1960",
            "1988"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1968"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which Greek god were the ancient Olympic Games dedicated?",
        "options": [
            "Apollo",
            "Zeus",
            "Athena",
            "Hera"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Zeus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ulrich Salchow won the first Olympic gold medal awarded for which sport?",
        "options": [
            "Biathlon",
            "Diving",
            "Figure skating",
            "Speed skating"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Figure skating"
    },
    {
        "question": "When were the last pure gold medals awarded at the Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1952",
            "1938",
            "1912"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1912"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 2020 Summer Olympics supposed to be held?",
        "options": [
            "Seoul",
            "Los Angeles",
            "Paris",
            "Tokyo"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "How often are the Olympic Games held?",
        "options": [
            "1 year",
            "8 years",
            "4 years",
            "12 years"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "4 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did basketball become an Olympic event?",
        "options": [
            "1948",
            "1932",
            "1928",
            "1936"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1936"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Olympian was stripped of his medals for the 1912 Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "Ivan Tsikhan",
            "Ben Johnson",
            "Ross Rebagliati",
            "Jim Thorpe"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Jim Thorpe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country does not dip its flag at the Olympics?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "Belgium",
            "Greece",
            "Portugal"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an Olympic sport?",
        "options": [
            "skateboarding",
            "wrestling",
            "high jumping",
            "swimming"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "skateboarding"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which Olympic Games was the torch relay first introduced?",
        "options": [
            "Barcelona 1992 Olympic Games",
            "London 1908 Olympic Games",
            "Berlin 1936 Olympic Games",
            "Paris 1900 Olympic Games"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Berlin 1936 Olympic Games"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first Olympic Village built?",
        "options": [
            "Heidelburg West, Victoria",
            "Olympiakyl\u00e4, Helsinki",
            "Zappelon, Athens",
            "Baldwin Hills, Los Angeles"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Baldwin Hills, Los Angeles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who designed the Olympic flag?",
        "options": [
            "William Penny Brookes",
            "Jules-Cl\u00e9ment Chaplain",
            "\n\nJuan Ant\u00f3nio Samaranch",
            "Pierre de Coubertin"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Pierre de Coubertin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color ring is not in Olympics Flag ?",
        "options": [
            "white",
            "red",
            "green",
            "black"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "white"
    }
]